The skeleton has
bones in an adult
Babies have 270
which fuse for this result
The skeleton is divided
into two main zones
which are called the axial and appendicular bones
The axial skeleton is topped by the skull
Your brain is in the cranium which acts as a hull
The mandible or jawbone is able to expand
which is useful for talking, as you can understand
The ossicles are small bones found inside your ear
The maleus, incus, stapes, which all help you hear
Sound waves are amplified by these three bones
And then move to the cochlea which discerns the tones
The ribcage helps to protect the lungs and the heart
With 12 ribs on each side, the sternum in the front
Your vertebral column, made up of vertebrae
Are stacked up very neatly in a vertical array
The cervical vertebrae make up your neck
The spinal cord keeps your reflexes on deck
The ribs are supported by thoracic vertebrae
Lumbar ones are at the end of the spinal cord pathway
Five sacral vertebrae are fused to form your sacrum
Which holds your upper body and is found in your bum
Below it is the coccyx or the tailbone
In humans the coccyx has not really grown
The appendicular skeleton, 126 bones
In shoulders, arms and legs, as we have here shown
Your scapula, also known as your shoulderblade
Next to the clavicle or collarbone is laid
You have three arm bones, one above and two below
Here they come together to meet at the elbow
The bones of the forearm are the ulna and the radius
The humerus in the upper arm so don't you forget this
You have 54 bones in one hand and one wrist
Of carpals, metacarpals and phalanges these consist
The proximal, intermediate and distal phalanges
Make up your fingers which you can move with ease
Remember that your hands are where you find the carpals
And the feet are where you will find all your tarsals
The hip bone can be divided into three
The ilium, ischium and pubis as you can see
The bones in your leg, well there are four
The patella is your kneecap, and then there are three more
The tibia and fibula are found below the knee
And the femur's found above it, as we can all agree
There are 52 bones in your ankles and your feet
Once you know the hand bones, these will be a treat
There are the tarsals, metatarsals and phalanges
Remember that they are proximal, intermediate and distal
If you enjoyed this video, like and subscribe!
You can also support me by following the link to my Patreon
If you have any topics you'd like me to cover, please leave a comment :)